【The fate that cannot be liberated】
【无法解脱的命运】
[Episode 16]
[第16集]
It's a pity to marry
可惜联姻
I had a falling out with Jia Lin four years ago.
四年前与家琳闹翻了。
Your Majesty, what do you mean?
陛下，您是什么意思？
I'm planning to
我打算
try again.
再试一次。
For His Majesty and Miss He?
为了陛下和何小姐？
Isn't that appropriate?
这不太合适吧？
When did I say it was for myself?
我什么时候说过是为了我自己了？
When did I mention Jiuling?
我什么时候提到九灵了？
My brother is a bloodthirsty and violent man
我的兄弟是一个嗜血暴力的人
Who tortured and killed several concubines
谁折磨并杀害了数名妃子
When he was still the crown prince.
当他还是皇太子的时候。
Now he has been deposed
如今他已被废黜
and was imprisoned in his mansion.
并被囚禁在他的府邸中。
It had eaten away at his psyche.
它已经侵蚀了他的心灵。
If I want to find him a suitable marriage
如果我要给他找一个合适的婚姻
to improve his status
以提高他的地位
and bring him peace,
并给他带来平安，
Isn't this a good idea?
这不是个好主意吗？
what do you think?
你怎么认为？
That's great.
那太好了。
Are you talking about Princess Jialing Xilan?
你说的是嘉陵西兰公主吧
Your Majesty?
陛下？
No.
不。
- Another one. - Another one?
- 另一个。 - 另一个？
I will let Jiuling take revenge.
我会让九菱去报仇的。
After its completion,
其完成后，
I will take her
我会带她
come back to me.
回到我身边。
Miss.
女士。
Why are you standing outside?
你为什么站在外面？
I just gave Mr. Rong medicine.
我刚刚给荣先生上药了，
He kicked me out.
他把我赶了出去。
I don't know what he was doing in there alone.
我不知道他一个人在里面做什么。
You'd better check him out.
你最好检查一下他。
Rong Yu,
Rong Yu,
I'm back.
我回来了。
I also brought the snacks you wanted.
你想要的零食我也带来了。
Rong Yu, open the door.
容宇，开门。
You asked them, didn't you?
你问过他们，不是吗？
Don't you want to try it?
你不想尝尝吗？
Rong Yu, come out.
容宇，你出来吧。
Rong Yu.
Rong Yu.
I'm really worried about you.
我真的很担心你。
- Take it. - What are you doing?
- 拿着它。 - 你在干什么？
you you? ? ?
你-你？？？
- It's too long. - What do you mean?
- 时间太长了。 - 你是什么意思？
Are you saying it took me too long to come back?
你是说我回来的时间太长了吗？
Then why don't you open the door?
那你为什么不开门呢？
Are you trying to make me worry?
你是想让我担心吗？
how dare you?
你怎么敢？
Now you dare to mess with me.
现在你竟然敢来惹我。
I originally planned to
我本来打算，
But now I don't want to do this anymore.
但现在我不想再这样了。
I'm going to make some soup.
我要去煮点汤。
Oh my goodness!
哦，我的天啊！
You scared Zhanping away
你把展平吓跑了
Let me see your hands.
让我看看你的手。
Still very swollen.
还是肿得很厉害。
hurry up. Let's apply some more medicine.
快点。我们再涂点药吧。
Honey,
亲爱的，
That guy is bad news.
那家伙是个坏消息。
WHO？
WHO？
that person.
那个人。
I don't want you to see him.
我不想让你看到他。
What happened to him?
他究竟怎么了？
You spilled the tea yourself,
你自己打翻了茶，
Then you disrespectfully threw the cloth away
然后你不尊重地扔掉了布
He handed it to you.
他递给你的。
It seems that you are someone who needs to pay attention to your attitude.
看来你是 需要注意一下自己态度的人了。
I will pay attention to my attitude.
我会注意自己的态度。
I will be a very nice person.
我会是一个非常好的人。
I will try to learn how to read
我会努力学习如何阅读
and astrology.
和占星术。
I will also make a lot of money.
我也会赚很多钱。
Please do not? ? ?
请不要？？？
- Please do not? ? ? - What?
- 请不要？？？ - 什么？
Don't leave me for someone else.
不要为了别人而离开我。
When did I say I was leaving you to find someone else?
我什么时候说过要离开你 去找别人了？
Plus, you don't have to work that hard.
此外，你不必那么努力。
Do you still remember what I said when I was in Rongcheng?
还记得我在榕城时说过的话吗？
Rong Yu, listen. No matter what happens,
容宇，你听着。不管发生什么，
No matter what you become,
无论你成为什么，
You are always the best to me.
你对我来说永远是最好的。
This wasn't always the case.
并非一直如此。
Remember when I said I was going to take time off?
还记得我之前说过我要请假吗？
What I said was not entirely true.
我说的并不完全是实话。
I just wanted to annoy you.
我刚才是想惹恼你。
I hope you can laugh when you are happy
我希望你开心的时候可以开怀大笑
Cry when you are feeling down.
当你情绪低落时哭泣。
If you are in a bad mood,
如果你心情不好，
You can vent to me.
你可以向我发泄。
If you want to lie to me, that's okay.
如果你想对我撒谎， 那也没关系。
You don’t have to be the best young master in Jialin
你不必是 嘉林最好的少爷
Nor is he the young master of Xingxiang Pavilion.
也不是星象阁的少主。
You are just Rong Yu.
你只是容羽。
So just be yourself.
所以就做你自己吧。
If you want to learn reading or astrology
如果你想学习阅读或占星术
Go for it.
大胆试试吧。
But if not, no big deal.
但如果没有，也没什么大不了的。
I just want you to be happy.
我只希望你能开心。
If you want to become better,
如果你想变得更好，
I will do whatever it takes to heal you.
我会尽一切努力来治愈你。
As long as you are happy.
只要你开心就好。
As for making money,
至于赚钱，
If Rong's goes bankrupt
如果荣氏破产了
I will hit the road
我将上路
And become a female knight to support you.
并成为一名女骑士来支持你。
Miss,
女士，
Teacher Rong, how are you?
荣老师你好吗
and Zhangping
and Zhanping
doing?
正在做？
Hey, well done everyone.
嘿，每个人都做得很好。
Teacher Rong is studying
荣老师正在学习
more words
更多的话
every day,
每天，
He's been smiling a lot lately.
他最近笑得很开心。
He also asked Zhanping
他还问展平
If you come back after New Year.
如果你新年后回来的话。
I have a new maid.
我有一个新女佣。
Her martial arts skills are indeed very high
她的武术功力确实很高
So no need to worry
所以无需担心
Mr. Rong and Zhan Ping were bullied.
荣老爷和展平被欺负。
Zhan Ping has to scold you.
展平非得骂你不可
Several times a day.
一天几次。
I don’t know what Heshan is doing recently.
不知道鹤山最近在做什么
Because he's been gone for so long.
因为他已经离开这么久了。
Didn't even come back for the New Year
连过年都没有回来
Even though the young master was so kind to him before.
尽管少爷 之前对他那么好。
Don't come back. Don't come back.
别回来。别回来。
He was so angry that you left without taking care of Mr. Rong.
他气坏了，你 没有照顾容老爷子就走了。
within a few months,
在几个月内，
When Master Rong is no longer angry
当荣爷不再生气的时候
Or when Master Rong’s condition improves,
或者当容师傅病情好转时，
I'll let him talk to Master Rong
我会让他跟荣爷谈谈
You are allowed to go home.
允许您回家。
You once told me that you are small,
你曾对我说过，你是渺小的，
After a while no one will remember you.
过了一段时间就没有人会记得你了。
However, even if time passes,
然而，即使时光流逝，
those who really care about you
那些真正关心你的人
will always remember
会永远记得
And I miss you more and more.
并且越来越想念你。
Happy New Year!
新年快乐！
Wish you all the best.
祝你一切顺利。
What is your New Year's resolution?
你的新年愿望是什么？
Don't worry if this is difficult.
如果这很困难，请不要担心。
i will find a way
我会找到办法
Help you achieve this goal
帮助您实现这一目标
I don't have any wishes
我没有任何愿望
how so?
怎么会这样？
You must have some wishes. Even Zhan Ping has aspirations.
你一定有一些愿望。 就连展平也有愿望。
The lady gave me two gold bars.
夫人给了我两根金条。
Even the one from Heshan was given to me.
连鹤山的那张也给了我。
This will irritate him.
这会激怒他。
Newcomer, what is your wish?
新人，你的愿望是什么？
She's been here for a while
她来这里已经有一段时间了
And said nothing.
并且什么也没说。
Is she mute?
她是哑巴吗？
It doesn't matter if you don't speak.
你不说话也没关系。
You'd better not speak.
你最好不要说话。
Her name is Cheng Bi.
她的名字叫程碧。
C-Chengbi.
C-Chengbi.
This name is really hard to remember.
这个名字实在是太难记了。
What? ? ?
什么？？？
What is your wish?
你的愿望是什么？
It's all happening.
这一切都在发生。
[Gongsun's Mansion]
[Gongsun's Mansion]
Why cancel hunting plans?
为什么要取消狩猎计划？
Your Majesty,
陛下，
A murder recently occurred in the capital
首都最近发生了一起命案
It remains unresolved.
至今仍未解决。
This makes everyone anxious.
这让每个人都感到焦虑。
For the safety of His Majesty,
为了陛下的安全，
I think it's better to stay in the palace.
我觉得还是留在皇宫比较好。
So what do you mean
那么你的意思是
As long as I step out of the palace, I will be killed.
只要我走出皇宫， 我就会被杀。
Your Majesty,
陛下，
I? ? ?
我？？？
I'm just worried.
我只是担心。
Worry?
担心？
Are you so useless?
你们就这么没用吗？
We hold spring exams to select military attachés? ?
我们举行春季考试选武官？？
and Jinwu guards.
and Jinwu guards.
Did you elect a bunch of losers?
你们选出了一群失败者吗？
They couldn't even catch the suspect.
他们连嫌疑人都抓不到。
Maybe, we should hold another martial arts exam.
也许，我们应该再举行一次武术考试。
Hunt at the same time.
同时进行狩猎。
- I want to hand-pick people. - Yes, Your Majesty.
- 我想亲自挑选人员。 - 是的，陛下。
So we don't need to cancel the hunt at all.
所以我们根本不需要取消狩猎。
Send more people there then
到时候多派点人去
Follow His Majesty.
跟随陛下。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
That's a good idea, uncle.
这是个好主意，叔叔。
So let's do that.
那么我们就这样吧。
I see.
我明白。
Hunting plans all settled.
狩猎计划一切都已解决。
Don't bother me with this anymore.
别再用这个来烦我了。
Uncle, why are you here?
叔叔，你怎么来了？
I'm leaving now, Your Majesty.
我现在就离开，陛下。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
Recently, Mr. Qian from the salt transportation department,
日前， 盐运部门钱先生，
assassinated.
被暗杀。
Does your Majesty know about this?
陛下知道这件事吗？
The matter has been reported to the Department of Revenue and Population .
收入和人口部 已报告此事。
I have arranged for someone to comfort his family.
我已经安排人 去安慰他的家人了。
Incidentally,
顺便一提，
Department of Justice and Department of Income and Population
司法部 和收入和人口部
Efforts have been made to catch the perpetrators, but without success.
一直在共同努力 抓捕肇事者，但未能成功。
They did find the old guy
他们确实找到了那个老家伙
Misappropriating a large amount of salt tax.
挪用大量盐税。
I don't actually care about this
我其实并不关心这个
So I sent them to you.
所以我把它们寄给你了。
You don't blame me, do you?
你不会怪我吧？
How can this be?
这怎么可能？
It's the minister's job
这是部长的工作
To relieve the emperor's worries.
以解除皇帝的后顾之忧。
If possible, could you also try it?
如果可以的话，你是否也可以尝试一下
Recover misappropriated salt taxes?
追回被挪用的盐税？
Then,
然后，
There's nothing more for me to do.
我没什么可做的了。
Not really.
并不真地。
It's time to change managers
是时候更换经理了
for several salt pans
为数个盐田
The latest report from Sichuan stated that
四川最新报道称
They discovered vast salt pans.
他们发现了大片的盐田。
The salt tax was vital to the economy.
盐税对经济至关重要。
So the salt luck makes this position super important.
所以盐运使这个职位 超级重要。
I come to see your majesty today
今天我来见陛下
Just wanted to ask
只是想问问
If you have a candidate in mind
如果您心中有候选人
As the salt transport envoy.
为盐运使之职。
Excellent,
出色地，
Can you help me decide?
你能帮我做决定吗？
This matter is crucial,
这件事情至关重要，
So I want to hear your Majesty's opinion.
所以我想听听陛下的意见。
The Salt Transportation Department is the main tax department.
盐运司 是主要税务部门。
The previous salt transport envoy embezzled so much money.
上一任盐运使， 贪污了这么多银子。
It seems I really need
看来我真的需要
Consider candidates carefully.
仔细考虑候选人。
I thought General Yan’s second son,
我以为严将军的二儿子，
Yan Jin may be a good choice.
严瑾或许是一个不错的选择。
Even though he is new to the Ministry of Taxation and Population
尽管他是 税务和人口部的新人
his father and eldest brother
他的父亲和大哥
He has considerable prestige in the military.
在军中具有相当的威望。
He must be very capable
他一定很有能力
And not afraid of offending others.
并且不怕得罪别人。
He should be entrusted with important tasks.
他应该被委以重任。
I understand your Majesty's intention,
我明白陛下的用意，
I will consider it carefully.
我会仔细考虑的。
Hot water is coming.
热水来了。
This medicine needs to be taken once a day for five days.
这种药需要每天服用一次， 连续服用五天。
Then you will become super smart
之后你就会变得超级聪明
Well-known astrologer
人尽皆知的占星大师
Why does this pill fizz?
为什么这药丸会发出嘶嘶声？
This is a bit strange.
这有点奇怪。
Madam, there will be nothing wrong with this medicine, right?
夫人，这药不会有什么问题 吧？
This medicine should be fine.
这个药应该没问题。
I've tried it myself
我自己也尝试过
But I'm still worried about his frail health.
但我还是担心他身体虚弱，
So I split the doses.
所以我分开了剂量。
Don't go to an astrology center
不要去占星馆
Just stay home for the next few days.
接下来的几天就待在家里。
This way I can always take care of him.
这样我就可以一直照顾他了。
This is the last day.
这是最后一天了。
we will find
我们会发现
If Master Rong recovers
如果容大师康复了
When he wakes up this time, right?
这次他醒过来的时候吧？
He will definitely recover!
他一定会康复的！
Miss He.
何小姐。
Take good care of him.
好好照顾他。
Miss Tan is here
谭小姐来了
You go make some soup now.
你现在去煮点汤吧。
When Master Rong woke up,
当容师傅醒来时，
He will definitely be hungry.
他肯定会饿的。
OK
好的。
Rigorous investigation is currently underway.
目前正在进行严格调查。
Don't take any action yet.
暂时不要有任何动作。
Wait for my news
等我的消息吧
How are you?
你还好吗？
I am fine.
我很好。
everything is fine.
一切安好。
You always say that.
你总是这么说。
It would be great if I knew martial arts
如果我会武术就好了
I can protect you rain or shine.
我可以风雨无阻地保护你。
Everything you have done for me is enough.
你为我所做的一切 已经足够了。
I don't want to drag you into this mess.
我不想把你拖入这个烂摊子。
When all this is done,
当这一切都完成后，
We can do anything you want.
我们可以做任何你想做的事。
I will support you no matter what, even if it means risking my life.
无论如何，我都会支持你， 即使这意味着冒着生命危险。
Don't say that.
别说那样的话。
We all need to be safe and healthy.
我们都必须安全、健康。
I mean everyone.
我的意思是每个人。
you told me last time
你上次告诉过我
I heard you found a cure for Master Rong.
听说你找到了治愈容大师的方法。
How is he now?
他现在怎么样了？
Really? if he gets better
真的吗？如果他好起来的话
you can make a deal
你们可以达成协议
And together, right?
并且在一起，对吗？
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
There is no such thing as a deal.
没有达成协议这样的事情。
Now,
现在，
I just wish him the best.
我只是祝他一切顺利。
If it were the past, I would believe it.
如果是过去，我会相信。
Now you and Master Rong
现在你和容大师
Looks really in love.
看起来真的很相爱。
don't make fun of me
别取笑我
related to this matter.
与这件事有关。
He is just a child,
他还只是个孩子，
And don’t really understand things yet.
并且还没有真正理解事情。
He is close to me and dependent on me.
他离我很近并且依赖我
Because he only treats me as family.
因为他只把我当作家人。
He helped me and protected me,
他曾经帮助我、保护我，
even saved me
甚至救了我
When the He family encountered changes.
何家遭遇变故时。
Emotionally and rationally,
从情感和理性上来说，
He should be the most important person to me.
他应该是对我来说最重要的人。
I should always cherish him and protect him.
我应该永远珍惜他、保护他。
But this life,
但这一生，
I owe him so much.
我欠他太多了。
I could never fully repay him.
我永远无法完全报答他。
I've thought about it.
我已经考虑过了。
When he recovered,
当他康复后，
Even without me,
即使没有我，
he will still be
他仍然会是
Young Master of Xingxiang Pavilion
星象阁少主
No one dares to bully.
无人敢欺负。
We will go our separate ways.
我们将走各自的路。
After all, we weren't supposed to be together in the first place.
毕竟我们本来就不该在一起。
There is no need to continue to deceive yourself.
没必要继续欺骗自己。
As such a gentleman,
作为这样的绅士，
If one day he
如果有一天他
Discover
发现
In his most difficult time,
在他最困难的时候，
i abandoned him
我抛弃了他
And then married him as the daughter of a criminal
然后 以罪犯女儿的身份嫁给了他
To save myself,
为了拯救我自己，
He would have been absolutely disgusted.
他肯定会感到彻底的厌恶。
Even if he doesn't say anything,
就算他什么也不说，
How can I keep Mrs. Rong's name?
我怎么能保得住容太太的名头呢？
And drag him down?
并把他拖下去？
But you are not that person.
但你不是那样的人。
Who cares if you are?
谁在乎你是不是？
None of this matters.
这些都不重要。
What's important is that
重要的是，
you have to ask yourself
你必须问自己
Have you never liked Master Yung?
你从来没有喜欢过容大师吗？
I don't.
我没有。
I'm going back to my room now.
我现在就回房间了。
Teacher Rong,
荣老师，
haven't seen you for a long time.
好久不见。
Honey, I've been here a long time.
亲爱的，我已经在这里很久了。
I saw the moon a minute ago
一分钟前我看到了月亮
but i don't know why
但我不知道为什么
It disappears.
它消失了。
master? ? ?
掌握？？？
Master Rong.
荣师傅。
What?
什么？
Why do you call me that?
你为什么这样叫我？
5 years? ? ?
5年？？？
Five years have passed.
五年过去了。
I'm sure it will work this time.
我确信这次一定会成功。
Why does it still not work?
为什么它仍然不起作用？
If it doesn't work this time
如果这次还不行的话
I really don't know what to do.
我真的不知道该怎么办。
All because I was useless.
这一切都是因为我没用。
sorry.
对不起。
Hey, please don't cry, okay?
嘿，请别哭，好吗？
I am still the same Rong Yu.
我还是那个容宇。
or maybe
或者可能
You don't like it either
你也不喜欢
This Rong Yu who doesn’t understand anything,
这个什么都不懂的容羽，
do not understand anything,
什么都不懂，
nothing can be done
什么也做不了
For you.
为你。
Don't say that about yourself.
别这么说你自己。
You are always the best.
你永远是最好的。
No matter what happens,
不管发生什么，
No matter what you become,
无论你成为什么，
You are always the best Rongyu.
你永远是最好的容宇。
Really?
真的吗？
So why? ? ?
那么为什么？？？
why are you crying?
你哭什么？
I won't cry anymore.
我不会再哭了。
The moon is gone,
月亮不见了，
But the stars are still there.
但星星还在那里。
hurry up. Let's go stargazing
快点。我们去观星吧
look.
看。
No wonder you like stargazing so much.
难怪你这么喜欢观星。
Even though I can't know my fate,
纵使我无法得知命运，
Still looks beautiful.
看起来还是很漂亮。
How come I didn't notice this before?
我以前怎么没注意到这一点？
look! look! A shooting star!
看！看！一颗流星！
I've tied the knot for you. make a wish.
我已经给你打好了结。许个愿。
When you see a shooting star,
当你看到流星时，
tie a knot in your clothes
在你的衣服上打个结
Then make a wish.
然后许愿。
Then, God will hear your wishes.
那么，上帝就会听到你的愿望。
Then God will help you achieve it
那么神就会帮助你实现它
I've done it for you.
我已经为你做了。
Just make a wish.
就许个愿吧。
i wish i could see my wife
我希望我能见到我的妻子
every day
每天
Never leave her.
永远不要离开她。
Is this your wish?
这是你的愿望吗？
are you still thinking
你还在想
will i leave you?
我会离开你吗？
i want my husband
我希望我的丈夫
will live a safe and healthy life,
将过上安全健康的生活，
become
变得
A wizard who lived to be a hundred years old.
活到一百岁的巫师。
return,
还，
I hope
我希望
My husband can bully others
我老公就可以欺负别人了
But no one can bully him.
但没有人可以欺负他。
I also hope that? ? ?
我也希望？？？
Rong Yu, look! Meteor shower!
容宇，你看！流星雨！
Although the moon is gone, the stars are still there.
月亮虽然不见了，但星星还是有的。
If you can't recover,
如果你无法康复，
I will be with you.
我会和你在一起。
Rong Yu,
Rong Yu,
I will never leave you.
我永远不会离开你。
Do not be afraid.
别害怕。
A deposed emperor and a female general.
一个被废黜的皇帝和一个女将军。
It's hard outside,
外面很难，
I'm not even sure where we're going.
我什至不确定我们要去哪里。
over there.
在那边。
Actually,
实际上，
I can't promise you anything.
我不能向你保证任何事情。
I promise you
我答应你
Come back after dinner
吃完饭就回来
but I do not have.
但我没有。
I promise you
我答应你
I won't leave you alone
我不会丢下你一个人
In the capital,
在首都，
I will always protect you
我会永远保护你
but I do not have.
但我没有。
The future is uncertain.
未来是不确定的。
Neither can I? ? ?
我也不能？？？
I can't even promise you
我什至无法向你保证
I won't leave you again.
我不会再离开你了。
if i'm no longer here
如果我不再在这里
And neither is Mr. Rong,
而荣爷也不是，
Who else in the world
世界上还有谁
Can I accompany and protect you?
可以陪伴和保护你吗？
I can't leave you alone.
我不能让你孤单。
I know how hard it is to get through it alone
我知道独自一人度过难关有多难
So I don't want you to go through this again.
所以我不想让你再经历这样的事。
Rong Yu,
Rong Yu,
Do you want to? ? ?
你想要_____吗？？？
want to? ? ?
想要？？？
Have one? ? ?
有一个？？？
Cover yourself well. It's cold.
把自己掩饰得很好。是冷的。
Zhanping, come here.
展平，你过来。
I have something to say to you.
我有话要对你说。
[Gongsun's Mansion]
[Gongsun's Mansion]
The Regent's daughter had just been given a princess.
摄政王的女儿 刚刚被赐予公主。
Xunnan sent a message
寻楠发来消息
The purpose is to marry the princess.
目的是迎娶公主。
The Prince Regent was certainly excited.
摄政王当然很兴奋。
They were all prepared for this,
他们都为此做好了准备，
And too busy to care about anything else.
而且太忙了，无暇顾及其他事情。
Now the Regent's people are falling apart.
现在，摄政王的人民正在崩溃。
He can only use military symbols to bluff people.
他只能用军符来唬人。
Wang Dequan,
Wang Dequan,
How many days until the hunt?
距离狩猎还有多少天？
Three days.
三天。
Grinding ink. I need to write a letter.
磨墨。我需要写一封信。
From Heshan.
鹤山来的。
He won't be back for a while.
他暂时不会回来了。
[To Zhangping]
[To Zhanping]
How could Heshan do this?
鹤山怎么能这么做？
He has been home for so long and still hasn't come back.
他回家这么久了， 还没回来。
Does he not miss Master Rong at all?
他就一点也不想念容大师吗？
It's not his fault.
这不是他的错。
I should go talk to my uncle.
我应该去和我叔叔谈谈。
OK By the way, Teacher Rong,
好的。顺便说一句，荣老师，
Last time you asked me -
上次你要求我——
I'll go to the kitchen to make soup first.
我先去厨房煮汤。
Do you have anything to say?
你有什么话要说吗？
check it out.
看看这个。
What's this?
这是什么？
I can't wake you up.
我无法让你清醒过来。
Think of it this way.
这样想吧。
if you could have someone
如果你可以有一个人
Be as smart and cute as me by your side
像我一样聪明可爱在你身边
Then, even if one day I am not around.
那么，即使有一天 我不在身边。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
If you're not around, I'll be alone.
如果你不在身边，我就一个人呆着。
Can you stop being so childish?
你能别再幼稚了吗？
This is the best promise
这是最好的承诺
I can give it to you.
我可以给你。
- I'm going for a walk. - where are you going?
- 我要去散步。 - 你要去哪里？
???Under the sunset at dusk? ? ?
??? 黄昏夕阳下？？？
???I traveled thousands of miles to a distant place? ? ?
??? 我千里迢迢去远方？？？
???Playing the piano under the moonlight? ? ?
??? 月下弹琴？？？
???These drinks won’t make me forget? ? ?
??? 这些饮料不会让我忘记？？？
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
??? 我写下的对你的渴望？？？
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 我们的命运是写在纸上的？？？
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 就像最烈的酒一样？？？
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 命运无路可逃？？？
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
??? 回头一看，我看到你在等待？？？
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
??? 我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤？？？
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河???
???You quietly turned around and closed the marriage certificate? ? ?
??? 你悄悄转身 合上了婚书？？？
???Ask how many stars are there in the sky? ? ?
??? 问天上有多少颗星星？？？
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
??? 我写下的对你的渴望？？？
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 我们的命运是写在纸上的？？？
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 就像最烈的酒一样？？？
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 命运无路可逃？？？
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
??? 回头一看，我看到你在等待？？？
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
??? 我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤？？？
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河???
???I gently caress the guzheng, waiting for passers-by like you???
??? 我轻轻抚着古筝， 等待着你这样的路人???
???So you are my indissoluble bond? ? ?
??? 原来你就是我的不解之缘？？？